good evening a new partnership between a
major grocer and insurance provider is
Raising concerns about competition and
access to medication in this country man
life announcing coverage of certain
drugs will only apply at pharmacies
owned by law blw such as shoers drug
Mark and this kind of deal is more
common than you may think cdv's Jackie
peris joins us now with the details
Jackie Patricia these types of deals are
common in the US and there are more here
in Canada and it could affect not just
the competition in the pharmacy industry
but accessibility for those who need the
medic a when Mary Dixon Burke tried to
get her regular medication from her
local pharmacy Last Summer she was
surprised to learn about a major change
in order to still be covered for the
drug she had to change to a soes or a
Shopper's Drug Mart if she didn't she'd
have to pay herself I didn't understand
why I was being told where I would have
to get my medication from more and more
insurance companies and other large
corporations are getting together on
these deals manual life labl is the
latest it privileges the really big
players it means that the big franchises
the big networks of pharmacies the big
corporations like La Blas are going to
succeed and win most of these contracts
for preferred Pharmacy deals and as a
consequence your neighborhood pharmacy
the small Regional chains uh they're
going to suffer and people like Mary
face disruption no forget it um I should
be able to go whereever I want under
manual life's new agreement about 260
drugs meant to treat conditions like
Crohn's multiple sclerosis and cancer
will only be covered if filled at laa
own pharmacies like Shoppers the
challenge with that is that it does
limit Choice uh and it does um in in
some ways interrupt continuity of care
the Ontario Pharmacy Association says
they're working with the Canadian
pharmacists Association to file a
complaint with a competition Bureau we
want to make sure that there's open ppns
where any pharmacy can participate and
we would like to maintain the Integrity
of that trusted healthare to Patient
healthare provider to Patient
relationship in a statement manual life
says they chose a single service
provider in an effort to benefit our
customers and their employees meanwhile
lbla says the company is confident the
customer experience won't be
affected but remember Mary she didn't
have a choice and for anyone who doesn't
like Shoppers for instance well that
they won't have a choice if they have to
go with lbls and if but whether or not
they'd like it Graham all right ctv's
Jackie Paris live for us tonight thanks